Guide to the Institution for Social and Policy Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Institution for Social and Policy Studies, Yale University, records
1966-1976
RU 479
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15.25
(15 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, student files, and administrative and subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Institution for Social and Policy Studies. Topics include fellowships, internships, evaluations and the City Program.
Yale University. Institution for Social and Policy Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Biographical / Historical
The Institution for Social and Policy Studies (ISPS) at Yale aims to facilitate interdisciplinary inquiry in the social sciences and public policy.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, student files, and administrative and subject files documenting the activities and operations of the Institution for Social and Policy Studies. Topics include fellowships, internships, evaluations and the City Program.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Political planning -- Research; Research institutes; Social sciences -- Research; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Institution for Social and Policy Studies
- Records, circa 1966-1976; Accession 1977-A-020
  Conditions Governing Access
  Student Files (boxes 1-4) are restricted until January 1, 2051 as established by Yale Corporation regulations. The remainder of the accession is open for research.
  - Student Files
    Student files are closed until January 1, 2051 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Rejected applicants, 1969-1971, undated (Box 1)
    - Dropped major, 1972-1975 (Box 1)
    - Summer Internship Program, 1971 Jun-Aug, student working files, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - Reports on Summer Internships, (by Interns), 1968-1972, undated (Box 3)
    - Interns, A-W, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Applicants, C-Y, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Summer Interns, A-Z, 1973 (Box 3)
    - Study of the City, Majors, (Classes of), 1972, 1973, 1974, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence
    - Visiting Speakers, alph. File, 1968-1971 (Box 5)
    - Speakers, questionnaire about, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Alphabetical correspondence file, 1968-1970 (Box 6)
    - Administrative files, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Subject Files
    - Study of the City Program, courses and committees, misc. files relating to S.C., 1969-1973 (Box 7)
    - Fellowship Internship Programs, alpha. file, 1968-1974, undated (Box 8)
    - Catalogue copy, 1972-1973 (Box 8)
    - Omicron Delta Epsilon, 1968-1972 (Box 8)
    - Files of Douglas Yates, P-Y, 1972-1975 (Box 9)
    - Files weeded from current I.S.P.S.
      - A - M, 1967-1972 (Box 10)
      - N - Y, 1967-1972 (Box 11)
      - Clippings file (Box 11)
    - Intern evaluations, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Appointments committee (1/2 legal archive box), 1970-1974, undated (Box 12)
  - Working Papers, Numerical file, Not Restricted
    - [w-2] thru W4 - 22, 1972-1974 (Box 13)
    - W4 - 23 thru W5 - 16, 1974-1975 (Box 14)
- Records, 1968-1976; Accession 1994-A-027
  The materials are open for research.
  - Center for the Study of the City and Its Environment: Reports, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, General, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2 - 3)
  - Director's Reports
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Statements, 1970-1973; 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Reports, Proposals and Studies, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 9)
  - News Clippings, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Project for the Study of Higher Education and Project for the Study of Policy Analysis, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Proposal for Creation of Institute of Social Science, 1968 June (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Working Papers, 1969 November (Box 1, Folder 13)